<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title><![CDATA[Passbolt Blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[Passbolt Blog - Get the latest product updates, password management news, and security information]]></description><link>/</link><image><url>/favicon.png</url><title>Passbolt Blog</title><link>/</link></image><generator>Ghost 4.22</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 13:21:25 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Understanding How Open Source Projects Work]]></title><description><![CDATA[<h2 id="breaking-down-the-anatomy-of-open-source-projects-is-the-first-step-to-getting-involved-and-contributing-to-your-favorite-software">Breaking down the anatomy of open source projects is the first step to getting involved and contributing to your favorite software.</h2><hr><p>In a survey conducted with nearly 150 passbolt users, we discovered that a majority of those stated that they<em><em> do not </em></em>contribute to open source projects was because they</p>]]></description><link>/understanding-how-open-source-projects-workbreaking-down-the-anatomy-of-open-source-projects-is-the-first-step-to-getting-involved-and-contributing-to-your-favorite-software/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">618e4d4ebbad8e003b12a478</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Savary]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 11:20:41 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="/content/images/2021/11/Passbolt_Understand-open-source-projects.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="breaking-down-the-anatomy-of-open-source-projects-is-the-first-step-to-getting-involved-and-contributing-to-your-favorite-software">Breaking down the anatomy of open source projects is the first step to getting involved and contributing to your favorite software.</h2><hr><img src="/content/images/2021/11/Passbolt_Understand-open-source-projects.png" alt="Understanding How Open Source Projects Work"><p>In a survey conducted with nearly 150 passbolt users, we discovered that a majority of those stated that they<em><em> do not </em></em>contribute to open source projects was because they don&#x2019;t:</p><ul><li>know where to start <strong><strong>15%</strong></strong></li><li>have the necessary skills <strong><strong>50%</strong></strong></li><li>have the time <strong><strong>28.75%</strong></strong></li></ul><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="/content/images/2021/11/image.png" class="kg-image" alt="Understanding How Open Source Projects Work" loading="lazy" width="700" height="460" srcset="/content/images/size/w600/2021/11/image.png 600w, /content/images/2021/11/image.png 700w"></figure><p>We&#x2019;ve already addressed the fact that you probably do have the skills needed to contribute &#x2014; it&#x2019;s just a common misconception that programming is the only contribution that makes a difference.</p><p>As for having the time, contributions can be big or small. Every little bit counts. You shouldn&#x2019;t feel like you have to make a large contribution for it to be worthwhile. Something as simple as leaving your feedback or sharing an opinion in our forum is a valuable contribution!</p><p>What we want to focus on here is for those of you who don&#x2019;t know where to start. We&#x2019;ll break down the basics of open source projects to help get you going. And, hopefully, of course, inspire you to start getting involved with open source projects.</p><h2 id="the-cathedral-and-bazaar">The Cathedral and Bazaar</h2><p>Not every open source project follows the same organizational model. Some are very large and highly decentralized. The majority are quite small and centralized around a few key people.</p><p>Eric S. Raymond, in his essay/book <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Cathedral_and_the_Bazaar" rel="noopener ugc nofollow">The Cathedral and the Bazaar: Musings on Linux and Open Source by an Accidental Revolutionary</a>, contrasts 2 development models for free software; The Cathedral and The Bazaar.</p><p>According to Raymond, The Cathedral is where source code is available with a software release. The code developed between releases is only available to a restricted group of software developers.</p><p>The Bazaar model is where the code is developed over the internet publicly. Raymond credits Linus Torvalds (leader of the Linux kernel project) as the inventor of this type of free software model.</p><h2 id="anatomy-of-open-source-projects">Anatomy of open source projects</h2><p>There are a lot of people interested in open source projects &#x2014; maybe you heard a friend talk about one they&#x2019;re involved with. Perhaps you use open source software, like passbolt, in your daily life.</p><p>Breaking down the anatomy of open source projects is a great way to better understand what role you can play. Not everyone who codes is an open-source expert, and not all of us are developers anyways.</p><p>First things first, we need to break down the different elements of an open-source project.</p><h2 id="who%E2%80%99s-who">Who&#x2019;s who?</h2><p>Typically, in an open-source project, you&#x2019;ll find the following roles.</p><p><strong><strong>Original Author</strong></strong> &#x2192; The person who created the project and has the power to assign new roles to other members for project maintenance. Depending on the project this person can have a lot of influence and acquire the nickname of &#x201C;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Benevolent_dictator_for_life" rel="noopener ugc nofollow">Benevolent dictator for life</a>&#x201D;.</p><p><strong><strong>Owner</strong></strong> &#x2192; Has administrative ownership of the project (can be the same person as the author). In some projects, like passbolt, a company can be the owner.</p><p><strong><strong>Maintainers </strong></strong>&#x2192; Responsible for driving the vision and goals of the project. Usually, people who feel responsible for the direction of the project and are committed to improving it.</p><p><strong><strong>Contributors</strong></strong> &#x2192; Add to the project. They follow the same code review process, are subject to the same requirements on code style, etc.</p><p><strong><strong>Community Members/Users</strong></strong> &#x2192; Valuable members of the community who provide feedback about features, bug reports, etc.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="/content/images/2021/11/image-1.png" class="kg-image" alt="Understanding How Open Source Projects Work" loading="lazy" width="700" height="115" srcset="/content/images/size/w600/2021/11/image-1.png 600w, /content/images/2021/11/image-1.png 700w"></figure><h2 id="what%E2%80%99s-it-all-about">What&#x2019;s it all about?</h2><p>Now that you&#x2019;ve got a pretty good grasp of who&#x2019;s who in typical open source projects, we need to figure out what the project is about, find out about their licensing, guidelines, and any other information that will help you to take part.</p><p><strong><strong>License</strong></strong> &#x2014; Open source doesn&#x2019;t just mean access to the source code. All open-source projects must have an <a href="https://opensource.org/osd" rel="noopener ugc nofollow">OSI-approved</a> license! This license protects the freedom of the contributors and users.</p><p><strong><strong>Readme </strong></strong>&#x2014; A manual that explains how to get started with the project. A good README will have everything a potential contributor needs to know about the project.</p><p><strong><strong>How to Contribute</strong></strong> &#x2014; Guidelines that help people contribute and show what type of contributors are needed. This file isn&#x2019;t mandatory, but great when a project has one.</p><p><strong><strong>Code of conduct</strong></strong> &#x2014; A document that establishes the author and owner expectations for how the contributors and participants behave. Usually used to create and maintain a safe and positive environment with the community.</p><h2 id="sharing-is-caring">Sharing is caring</h2><p>Beyond creating a positive environment in an open-source community, most projects will also want to ensure that users and contributors feel comfortable enough to share, and be open about their opinions. While also making sure that contributors know how valuable their code, feedback, or any other contributions are.</p><p>Some of the tools open source projects will use to make this possible include:</p><ul><li>Issue Tracker &#x2014; Where people discuss issues related to the project</li><li>Pull Requests &#x2014; Where people review changes in progress</li><li>Synchronous Chat Channel &#x2014; Specifically meant for people to share their ideas and have conversations (like Slack, or a forum)</li></ul><p>At passbolt, we use <a href="https://github.com/passbolt" rel="noopener ugc nofollow">Github</a> for Issue Tracking and Pull Requests. For discussions, we have our <a href="https://community.passbolt.com/" rel="noopener ugc nofollow">community forum</a>.</p><h2 id="why-contribute-to-passbolt%E2%80%99s-project">Why contribute to passbolt&#x2019;s project?</h2><p>Well, we&#x2019;ve determined you <em><em>must </em></em>have some skills that are valuable to passbolt&#x2019;s open-source software. Plus, now you know exactly who&#x2019;s who and what&#x2019;s what in typical open source projects.</p><p>Your contributions help to continue the development of passbolt, and the features that users are looking for. The more features there are, and the better they are means that we can continue to grow, together.</p><p>The added bonus is getting to be a part of a wonderful community. The passbolt community is pretty tight-knit, very supportive, and we&#x2019;re always welcoming new insights, ideas, and skillsets. Join in!</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Passbolt browser integration just got an upgrade]]></title><description><![CDATA[<h3 id="based-on-users-feedback-it-was-time-for-passbolt-to-upgrade-some-of-the-browser-extension-integration-features-primarily-the-auto-fill-auto-save-functionalities">Based on <a href="https://community.passbolt.com/t/as-a-user-the-passbolt-extension-can-auto-fill-my-passwords-in-forms/82" rel="noopener ugc nofollow">users feedback</a>, it was time for passbolt to upgrade some of the browser extension integration features, primarily the auto-fill / auto-save functionalities.</h3><hr><p>While browsing the internet, passbolt users aren&#x2019;t always aware when credentials are known by passbolt, for a given web form. This is when you need</p>]]></description><link>/passbolt-browser-integration-just-got-an-upgrade/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">618e4860bbad8e003b12a428</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Savary]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 11:04:39 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="/content/images/2021/11/Passbolt_browser-integration.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="based-on-users-feedback-it-was-time-for-passbolt-to-upgrade-some-of-the-browser-extension-integration-features-primarily-the-auto-fill-auto-save-functionalities">Based on <a href="https://community.passbolt.com/t/as-a-user-the-passbolt-extension-can-auto-fill-my-passwords-in-forms/82" rel="noopener ugc nofollow">users feedback</a>, it was time for passbolt to upgrade some of the browser extension integration features, primarily the auto-fill / auto-save functionalities.</h3><hr><img src="/content/images/2021/11/Passbolt_browser-integration.png" alt="Passbolt browser integration just got an upgrade"><p>While browsing the internet, passbolt users aren&#x2019;t always aware when credentials are known by passbolt, for a given web form. This is when you need to click on the passbolt icon in the browser toolbar to check manually.</p><p>That&#x2019;s why the much awaited in-form integration has arrived. You&#x2019;ll be able to perform actions faster within web forms, and be able to quickly generate passwords and save resources.</p><p>Check out below how it works, as well as the variety of other improvements we have brought to the browser extension.</p><h2 id="in-form-integration">In-form integration</h2><p>The new in-form integration will change the way you use passbolt daily. You&#x2019;ll be able to auto-fill forms with suggested credentials, and generate new and randomised passwords based on the data you fill in.</p><h3 id="auto-fill-a-form-with-suggested-credentials">Auto-fill a form with suggested credentials</h3><p>When you&#x2019;re filling in an online form, and already have credentials saved in passbolt for that URL, a suggestion will appear in the field you&#x2019;re ready to type in.</p><p>When you click on the field, an icon will show up on the right side that will allow you to auto-fill your username and password into the fields required.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-card-hascaption"><img src="https://miro.medium.com/max/60/0*6HdhuGiOmDhzxVCu?q=20" class="kg-image" alt="Passbolt browser integration just got an upgrade" loading="lazy"><figcaption>Fig. auto-fill credentials with in-form integration</figcaption></figure><p><br>Generate a new randomised password without leaving your form</p><p>Easily generate new randomised passwords when signing up in new URLs. To do this, click on the &#x201C;Generate a password securely&#x201D; from the in-form integration.</p><h3 id="save-typed-credentials-in-just-a-click">Save typed credentials in just a click</h3><p>New sign up, requiring a new username and password? Not a problem. You can now save new credentials automatically using the in-form integration.</p><p>After using the &#x201C;Generate a password securely&#x201D; functionality, your passbolt browser extension will detect that a form has been filled in and offer for you to save it automatically.<br></p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-card-hascaption"><img src="https://miro.medium.com/max/700/0*HmgbZ9Sa4xfWXKBO" class="kg-image" alt="Passbolt browser integration just got an upgrade" loading="lazy"><figcaption>Fig. generating a new randomised password directly from a form, and saving automatically</figcaption></figure><h2 id="bigger-and-better-quick-access">Bigger and better quick access</h2><p>You&#x2019;ll notice that the size of the quick access has been increased for improved visual comfort.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://miro.medium.com/max/700/1*JR-7lPdaHjmGQmD9OF_COw.png" class="kg-image" alt="Passbolt browser integration just got an upgrade" loading="lazy"></figure><h2 id="other-improvements">Other improvements</h2><p>The browser extension icon itself will change colour depending on your connection status &#x2014; it will be grey when you aren&#x2019;t logged in and then turn red when you are. This visual clue will make it easier for you to see when you are or aren&#x2019;t logged in with your browser extension.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="/content/images/2021/11/Passbolt_icons.png" class="kg-image" alt="Passbolt browser integration just got an upgrade" loading="lazy" width="700" height="233" srcset="/content/images/size/w600/2021/11/Passbolt_icons.png 600w, /content/images/2021/11/Passbolt_icons.png 700w"></figure><p>There will also be a visual clue when the extension has matching credentials for a form that&#x2019;s displayed on the current page when you&#x2019;re logged in to your passbolt account.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-card-hascaption"><img src="/content/images/2021/11/Passbolt_password-generator.png" class="kg-image" alt="Passbolt browser integration just got an upgrade" loading="lazy" width="360" height="575"><figcaption>Fig. password generator in quick access</figcaption></figure><h3 id="quick-access-improvements">Quick access improvements</h3><p>Items will be directly clickable in the suggestions list displayed in your browser extension. You won&#x2019;t need to go to a different section and click &#x201C;use on this page&#x201D; anymore.</p><p>Also, the password generator will now be available directly from the browser extension quick access when you&#x2019;re creating a credential and want to change the generation parameters (characters, length, etc..).</p><h1 id="your-valuable-feedback">Your valuable feedback</h1><p>Your opinion matters. The browser extension improvements are based on the feedback we received from our community. Let us know what you think about the latest release v3.3 and these improvements <a href="https://community.passbolt.com/t/new-release-v3-3-0-senior-elfo/4405" rel="noopener ugc nofollow">in the community forum</a>.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="/content/images/2021/11/Passbolt_feedback-CTA.png" class="kg-image" alt="Passbolt browser integration just got an upgrade" loading="lazy" width="700" height="115" srcset="/content/images/size/w600/2021/11/Passbolt_feedback-CTA.png 600w, /content/images/2021/11/Passbolt_feedback-CTA.png 700w"></figure>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>